Vikramjeet Gill . Jarvis Consulting

My name is Vikramjeet Gill. I am a recent graduate of York University and I have a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I am a software developer here at Jarvis. Before working at Jarvis I worked for a nonprofit called Software For Love mostly doing front-end work designing websites for clients including charities. Before that, I was working as a student success mentor lead at York where I was responsible for managing our Peer Helper program and leading a team of over 30 people. What excites me most about the software development industry is the opportunity to work on a wide variety of projects in many industries. Businesses in every sector of the economy require software developers so as a developer you have the option of working for whatever sector you want ranging from banking to big tech to gaming to aerospace to E-commerce and more.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git Competent: Python, React, NodeJS, Bootstrap, Javascript

Familiar: Angular, Typescript, C++, AWS, C

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_VikramjeetGill

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]:

- Developed a series of bash scripts designed to capture host hardware specification data and host hardware resource usage data and update and report said usage data on a minute by minute basis.
- host_info.sh captures host hardware specification data and host_usage.sh captures resource usage data. psql_docker.sh is used to interact with and manage the required docker container
- Used PostgreSQL for database management and to store collected information.

Highlighted Projects

Unova Pokedex [GitHub]: Created interactive web app that serves as an encyclopedia for the 5th generation of Pokémon to develop HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other web development skills. Used React and Bootstrap frameworks for frontend to develop the user interface.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (November 2023 - present): Built multiple applications both for internal use and for clients. Applied the Agile framework implementation Scrum to coordinate with team members to produce software. Utilized PostGreSQL to design database for internal applications.

Software Developer, Software For Love (May 2023 - September 2023): Utilized React, Bootstrap, and other front-end frameworks to develop user interfaces for client websites. Applied UI and UX design principles to design client websites. Worked with a team of over a dozen other developers and designers to develop software solutions for clients.

Student Success Mentor Lead, York University (September 2022 - April 2023): Managed a team of over 30 employees and volunteers to provide academic advising and student support services to computer science and engineering students. Planned and lead academic orientation events for over 400 first year computer science, digital media, and engineering students. Organized learning skills workshops, Leetcode practice sessions, and faculty panels. Wrote Python scripts to analyze student related data.

Education

York University (2018-2023), Honours Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Lassonde School of Engineering

Miscellaneous

- Marathon Runner
- Powerlifter